<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>pd⚇Tech</title>
  
  <subtitle>Mind entanglement</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://pudongtech.top/"/>
  <updated>2018-09-24T02:52:44.826Z</updated>
  <id>http://pudongtech.top/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Pu Dong</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Thoughts about trade war</title>
    <link href="http://pudongtech.top/2018/09/21/tradewar/"/>
    <id>http://pudongtech.top/2018/09/21/tradewar/</id>
    <published>2018-09-21T14:40:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-09-24T02:52:44.826Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<script src="/assets/js/APlayer.min.js"> </script><pre><code>“Old war has gone  Collapse of old economic order has begun  Acient dragon is awake and so strong? Yet winter is coming”  </code></pre><a id="more"></a><p>The police of Chinese economy reform has been giving significant boost to economy and enormous opportunities to its people.<br>This diligent nation grasp this golden opportunity.<br>The last four decades’ history is thus been composed and witnesses the awake of an acient dragon who has a glorious and resplendent past. </p><p>Recent ten years, so many things changed.<br>Smart phones are commonly used by almost everyone and function extensively  covering  from living to work, from eating to shopping…<br>The cost of housing seems getting out of control and up more than ten times.<br>And…<br>President Xi has served almost ten year, I dont know exactly.<br>Maybe the most importantly, the constitution has been amended and approved of the time in place.<br>Its really hard to stay wise on an eminence. Talk with respect.</p><p>What really makes anxious is the seemly total economic war against the United States of America.<br>China changes a lot, but is still far away strong.<br>Nowadays, the poverty is not exposed to public.<br>The citizens do not know and do not want to know that as it is none business to them.<br>However, to this nation, to this people’s republic, its important.<br>I think this war brings no good to us, and in the near future we young people would struggle to take care of our whole family.<br>It is observed that too much money has been invest to amusement and too many people are devoted to making money in entertainment industry.</p><p>As the former president John kennedy’s speech:</p><blockquote><p>We choose to go to the Moon! We choose to go to the Moon in this decade and do the other things, not because they are easy, but because they are hard; because that goal will serve to organize and measure the best of our energies and skills, because that challenge is one that we are willing to accept, one we are unwilling to postpone, and one we intend to win, and the others, too.</p></blockquote><p>We need this spirit and keep it in mind.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;“Old war has gone  
Collapse of old economic order has begun  
Acient dragon is awake and so strong? 
Yet winter is coming”  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="diary" scheme="http://pudongtech.top/categories/diary/"/>
    
    
      <category term="小学生英语作文" scheme="http://pudongtech.top/tags/%E5%B0%8F%E5%AD%A6%E7%94%9F%E8%8B%B1%E8%AF%AD%E4%BD%9C%E6%96%87/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>常用检索网站</title>
    <link href="http://pudongtech.top/2018/03/19/scholar/"/>
    <id>http://pudongtech.top/2018/03/19/scholar/</id>
    <published>2018-03-19T07:31:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-03-19T09:17:06.423Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<script src="/assets/js/APlayer.min.js"> </script><a id="more"></a><p><a href="http://people.sc.fsu.edu/~jburkardt/m_src/m_src.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MATLAB source code</a><br><a href="http://people.sc.fsu.edu/~jburkardt/py_src/py_src.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Python source code</a><br><a href="https://sci-hub.org.cn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google scholar mirror</a><br><a href="http://ac.scmor.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google mirror</a><br><a href="https://discuss.sci-hub.org.cn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">scihub 中文社区</a><br><a href="http://sci-hub.tw/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">scihub (不定时更新)</a><br><a href="https://www.scopus.com/search/form.uri?display=basic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">scopus database</a><br><a href="http://gen.lib.rus.ec" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Library Genesis</a><br><a href="http://en.booksee.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">bookesee (Library)</a><br><a href="http://booksc.org/s/?q=&amp;t=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">booksc (Library)</a><br><a href="http://www.ti.com/ww/tw/analog/webench/webench-filters.shtml" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Filter Design</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;script src=&quot;/assets/js/APlayer.min.js&quot;&gt; &lt;/script&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://people.sc.fsu.edu/~jburkardt/m_src/m_src.html&quot; target
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="collection" scheme="http://pudongtech.top/categories/collection/"/>
    
    
      <category term="scholar" scheme="http://pudongtech.top/tags/scholar/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Thoughts of Freund&#39;s Timoshenko Medal Lecture</title>
    <link href="http://pudongtech.top/2017/12/18/Freund/"/>
    <id>http://pudongtech.top/2017/12/18/Freund/</id>
    <published>2017-12-18T14:44:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-12-20T08:33:13.335Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<script src="/assets/js/APlayer.min.js"> </script><pre><code>The Timoshenko Medal is an award given annually by the American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) to an individual &quot;in recognition of distinguished contributions to the field of applied mechanics.&quot;</code></pre><a id="more"></a><p><a href="http://imechanica.org/node/196" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reading Material</a></p><p>In this lecture, Freund gave a brief description on his experiences of academic journey. Unlike de Gennes’s experiences that were talked in his Nobel prize speech, Freund did have more experiences in engineering and other jobs, not only scientific research. Freund gradually found his area which he was actually interested in. This exploiting process really has many indications to us. Scientific research is endless, pursuing shall never stop.  </p><p>Freund also talked about the future of mechanics. Though this lecture was given in 2003, his judgement that a sound fundamental mechanics theory is of great use meanwhile the advance utility for demonstration is also appreciated is still referable.  </p><p>As recently developed, the interaction between solid mechanics and material science is strengthened. Many researchers step into this multidisciplinary area. This point was also mentioned in Freund’s lecture. Actually, this kind of interaction in science is irreversible, we PhD students should prepare for it and explore fearlessly.  </p><p>Freund did emphasize that “A professional career is rarely a solitary endeavor, and that is surely so in my case. There are many people who have earned a portion of the recognition handed to me tonight.” Freund thanked his colleagues and students at the end of this lecture. Scientific research needs not only endeavors but also communicating.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;The Timoshenko Medal is an award given annually by the American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) to an individual &amp;quot;in recognition of distinguished contributions to the field of applied mechanics.&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Reading Thoughts" scheme="http://pudongtech.top/categories/Reading-Thoughts/"/>
    
    
      <category term="小学生英语作文" scheme="http://pudongtech.top/tags/%E5%B0%8F%E5%AD%A6%E7%94%9F%E8%8B%B1%E8%AF%AD%E4%BD%9C%E6%96%87/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Draw conclusions and spread ideas</title>
    <link href="http://pudongtech.top/2017/12/12/writepaper/"/>
    <id>http://pudongtech.top/2017/12/12/writepaper/</id>
    <published>2017-12-12T15:36:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-12-20T08:22:37.770Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<script src="/assets/js/APlayer.min.js"> </script><p><img src="http://p0cjrqf63.bkt.clouddn.com/whitesides.png" alt="whitesides"><br><a id="more"></a></p><p><a href="https://gmwgroup.harvard.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ReadingMaterial</a><br><a href="http://p0cjrqf63.bkt.clouddn.com/writepaper.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SupplementaryPaper~HowToWriteAPaper</a><br>–“Interesting and unpublished” is equivalent to “non-existent”<br>notes after reading Prof. George M. Whitesides’s essay</p><p>Last week, I spent several hours reading this short essay which can be read roughly in only half an hour or less. While reading this paper, I went through my past academic experiences, though it is quite short, and found that once upon a time I was in the situation as George described: I completed my research program and learned from it, which is meaningful enough with or without a research paper or a conclusive report. The statement made by George that “Interesting and unpublished” is equivalent to “non-existent”. This really touches me a lot. </p><p>Similarly, my supervisor told me that whatever you have done and however the significance is, you should draw some conclusions and write some articles. At that time, I did not fully understand it. But now, my viewpoint has changed that all of the work we researchers do like operating analysis, doing experiments, reading papers, etc. are to develop our own ideas and theories to better understand this natural world for mankind and win a better life for ourselves. So they shall not be concealed unintentionally by ourselves but spread and communicated with peers and make some advances in our fields.<br>Also，George made lots of concrete advices on how to write a good scientific paper efficiently, which needs practicing and being carried out in my daily writing tasks. Really useful reading material!</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://p0cjrqf63.bkt.clouddn.com/whitesides.png&quot; alt=&quot;whitesides&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Reading Thoughts" scheme="http://pudongtech.top/categories/Reading-Thoughts/"/>
    
    
      <category term="小学生英语作文" scheme="http://pudongtech.top/tags/%E5%B0%8F%E5%AD%A6%E7%94%9F%E8%8B%B1%E8%AF%AD%E4%BD%9C%E6%96%87/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Thoughts after reading Gennes’ Nobel lecture</title>
    <link href="http://pudongtech.top/2017/12/06/Gennes/"/>
    <id>http://pudongtech.top/2017/12/06/Gennes/</id>
    <published>2017-12-06T13:02:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-12-20T08:19:18.377Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<script src="/assets/js/APlayer.min.js"> </script><pre><code>“Have fun on sea and land  Unhappy it is to become famous  Riches, honors, false glitters of this world  All is but soap bubbles”  </code></pre><a id="more"></a><p><a href="http://p0cjrqf63.bkt.clouddn.com/gennes-lecture.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reading Material_Gennes’ Lecture</a></p><p>Pierre-Gilles de Gennes used this poetry to convey his general feeling of the honor of Nobel prize. What fascinates him is the “amusing” science as well as unusual experimental phenomena. In contrast, this unattainable prize for most researchers and accompanying riches, etc. to him are like the soap bubbles. It might be exaggerated, however, after reading this lecture I truly appreciate some of his feelings. </p><p>This lecture was started by the scientific concept of “soft matter”, then de Gennes shared his understanding. After that de Gennes began to talk about some mechanical properties of dilute coils, surfactants, liquid crystals, ferrosmectic, etc. Last but not least, he also gave some of his viewpoints on the relationship between experiments and theory. Almost all of this lecture was focused on research and science. The “soap bubbles” of this world are not the funny thing to him, but the “amusing” science is.  </p><p>The observation of the conformations of a flexible chain de Gennes mentioned has become the key to later developments in polymer statistics. This really makes me think a lot. In my field, most of the phenomena have been predicted by the fore-distinguished scientist theoretically. At that point, an unusual phenomenon which might not coincide with the previous one needs special attention, which may be a potential breakthrough.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;“Have fun on sea and land  
Unhappy it is to become famous  
Riches, honors, false glitters of this world  
All is but soap bubbles”  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Reading Thoughts" scheme="http://pudongtech.top/categories/Reading-Thoughts/"/>
    
    
      <category term="小学生英语作文" scheme="http://pudongtech.top/tags/%E5%B0%8F%E5%AD%A6%E7%94%9F%E8%8B%B1%E8%AF%AD%E4%BD%9C%E6%96%87/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Thoughts after reading about Jan D. Achenbach</title>
    <link href="http://pudongtech.top/2017/12/04/Achenbach/"/>
    <id>http://pudongtech.top/2017/12/04/Achenbach/</id>
    <published>2017-12-03T16:57:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-12-20T08:34:51.821Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<script src="/assets/js/APlayer.min.js"> </script><pre><code>Jan Drewes Achenbach (born 20 August 1935) is a professor emeritus (Walter P. Murphy Professor and Distinguished McCormick School Professor) at Northwestern University. </code></pre><p><img src="http://p0cjrqf63.bkt.clouddn.com/achenbach_h.jpg" alt="achenbach_h"><br><a id="more"></a></p><blockquote><p><a href="http://imechanica.org/node/185" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reading Material_1</a><br><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jan_D._Achenbach" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reading Material_2</a></p></blockquote><p>Jan D. Achenbach, known for his contributions on the solid mechanics, is a member of US National Academy of Sciences and National Academy of Engineering and was honored the Timoshenko Medal, which is the highest award in mechanics community. He has published more than 300 research papers and developed methods for flaw detection and characterization by using contact transducers, imaging techniques, and laser-based ultrasonics. He has been extensively cooperating with investigators from other universities and from industrial organizations on both theoretical and experimental projects.<br>Absolutely, he is a great scientist. What impressed me a lot is that he has cultivated so many distinguished scientists such as L. B. Freund, who is also a Timoshenko Medalist. As far as I know, he also directly or indirectly guided a number of outstanding mechanicians born in China, e. g. Yonggang Huang, Zhigang Suo and Huajian Gao, though I’m not quite sure about this. Indeed, he helped a lot on the higher education and research of China and also contributed a lot in advocating the academic communications of the whole world. I think that he is more of an educationist than just a scientist.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Jan Drewes Achenbach (born 20 August 1935) is a professor emeritus (Walter P. Murphy Professor and Distinguished McCormick School Professor) at Northwestern University. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://p0cjrqf63.bkt.clouddn.com/achenbach_h.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;achenbach_h&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Reading Thoughts" scheme="http://pudongtech.top/categories/Reading-Thoughts/"/>
    
    
      <category term="小学生英语作文" scheme="http://pudongtech.top/tags/%E5%B0%8F%E5%AD%A6%E7%94%9F%E8%8B%B1%E8%AF%AD%E4%BD%9C%E6%96%87/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>网站设置基本完成</title>
    <link href="http://pudongtech.top/2017/12/01/individual/"/>
    <id>http://pudongtech.top/2017/12/01/individual/</id>
    <published>2017-12-01T09:29:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-12-01T09:41:34.407Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<script src="/assets/js/APlayer.min.js"> </script><p>10月初捣鼓了一两天，有事耽搁就扔在那了，这两天好好看了看hexo和主题的官方文档，稍微顺利一些（网上博客的一些总结很好，但是很多过了时效。）。先配置Hexo的环境，然后同时po到github和codingme，分国内外dns，加载速度要好一些，算是个一劳永逸的活吧。<br>再就是配置next主题的各项配置了，官方文档需要更新了。。。分享页面那里折腾了很久，因为以前的分享方法基本不管用了，最后用的sharesdk。<br>博客的网页是搭好了，真正关键的是内容，希望自己平时能更一些对自己有益对大家有益的东西吧。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;script src=&quot;/assets/js/APlayer.min.js&quot;&gt; &lt;/script&gt;&lt;p&gt;10月初捣鼓了一两天，有事耽搁就扔在那了，这两天好好看了看hexo和主题的官方文档，稍微顺利一些（网上博客的一些总结很好，但是很多过了时效。）。先配置Hexo的环境，然后同时
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="diary" scheme="http://pudongtech.top/categories/diary/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Dude-fussing" scheme="http://pudongtech.top/tags/Dude-fussing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
